Guide to the George Leon Walker and Williston Walker Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
George Leon Walker and Williston Walker Papers
1722-1979
RG 51
Yale University Divinity School Library
4
(9 boxes)
Correspondence, diaries, notes and writings of George Leon and Williston Walker form the core of the collection and provide extensive biographical information. They detail the activities of a typical New England clergyman during the second half of the 19th century and provide information on national news, political events, the Civil War, the slavery issue, financial news on currency and taxes, and daily weather conditions. Also included are records of sermons preached and pastoral records. George Leon Walker (1830-1900) was a Congregational clergyman in Portland, Maine (1858-1867), New Haven, Connecticut (1868-1873), and Hartford, Connecticut (1879-1892). He was a corporate member of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions and served on the commission to prepare the Congregational creed. His son, Williston Walker (1860-1922) was professor of history/church history at Bryn Mawr College (1888-1889), Hartford Theological Seminary (1889-1901) and Yale University (1901-1922). He also served as a trustee of Amherst College (1896-1922), acting dean of Yale Graduate School (1916-1917) and provost of Yale University (1919-1922).
Walker, George Leon, 1830-1900
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Chronology of George Leon Walker
1830 Apr 30 Born in Rutland, Vt. Walker studied law in Boston before studying theology with his father, Charles Walker.
1857-1859 Post-graduate student at Andover Theological Seminary.
1858 Honorary M.A., Middlebury College.
1858 Sep Married Maria Williston who became the mother of his two sons, Williston and Charles.
1858-1867 Pastor at State St. Church, Portland, Me.
1865 Maria Williston Walker died.
1867 Forced to resign his pastorale due to illness, but continued to preach occasionally throughout New England.
1868-1873 Pastor of the First Church in New Haven, Ct.
1869 Jul Son Charles died.
1870 D.D., Yale University.
1870 Sep Married Amelia R. Lamed.
1874-1879 Forced to resign his pastorale due to illness, Walker traveled to Europe and preached fairly regularly at various places throughout New York and New England, often at Brattleboro, Vt.
1875-1878 Acting Pastor of the Centre Church, Brattleboro, Vt.
1877 Appointed a corporate member of the American Board of C. for F.M.
1879-1892 Pastor of the First Church in Hartford, Ct. Illness caused his resignation in 1892 but he continued to preach occasionally through 1896.
1880 Trip to England.
1883 On the commission to prepare the Congregational creed.
1887 Appointed fellow of Yale University.
1888-1896 Member, Board of Visitors, Andover Theological Seminary.
1890 Trip to England.
1896 Aug Suffered a paralytic stroke.
1900 Mar 14 Died.
History of the First Church in Hartford (1884)
Thomas Hooker, Preacher, Founder, Democrat (1891)
Some Aspects of the Religious Life of New England (1897)
Biographical information taken from: Who Was Who in America (Vol. 1, 1897-1942); Andover Theological Seminary, General Catalogue, 1808-1909; Schaff-Herzog Encyclopedia of Religious Knowledge.
Chronology of Williston Walker
1860 Jul 1 Born in Portland, Me., son of George Leon and Maria Williston Walker
1883 B.A., Amherst College
1886 B.D., Hartford Theological Seminary
1886 Married Alice Mather
1888 Dr.Phil., University of Leipzig
1888-1889 Associate professor of history, Bryn Mawr College
1889-1892 Associate professor of church history, Hartford Theological Seminary
1892-1901 Professor of Germanic and Western Church history, Hartford Theological Seminary
1896-1922 Trustee of Amherst College; secretary of corporation from 1901
1901-1922 Titus Street Professor of Ecclesiastical History, Yale
1916-1917 Acting dean of Yale Graduate School
1919-1922 Provost of Yale University
1922 Mar 9 Died
Walker served as president of the American Society of Church History and of the New Haven Colony Historical Society. He was a member of several other organizations concerned with the history of the colonial period. Walker published several books relating to Congregational Church history in New England and broader topics.
Biographical information taken from: Dictionary of American Biography, XIX, pp. 366-367.
Scope and Contents
I. Diaries of George Leon Walker
II. Miscellaneous Records
III. Correspondence
IV. Writings, Addresses, Sermons
V. Notes
VI. Personal Items and Memorabilia
The diaries and records of Series I and II were received and processed in 1978; the remaining material was added in 1982. The correspondence, diaries, notes and writings of George Leon and Williston Walker form the core of this collection, but significant documentation is also provided by letters of others, papers, and clippings which the Walkers' interest in history led them to collect. Correspondence of William Jennings Bryan and sermons of early New England clergymen Payson Williston and Elisha Williams are among the documents included in the collection. As a member of the Board of Visitors of Andover Theological Seminary and a member of the Prudential Committee of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, George Leon Walker had a personal interest in the controversies which embroiled those bodies in the late 1800's and collected relevant documentation.
The diaries of George Leon Walker in Series I include sixteen volumes of daily entries dating from 1861 to 1896. Aim included in this Series are a small notebook describing Walker's trip to England in 1880 and a fragmentary diary of Walker's second wife, Amelia, written in 1898. Walker's diaries provide a detailed and complete account of the daily activities of a New England clergyman during the second half of the nineteenth century and supply extensive biographical information. Walker was interested in national news and politics and reported important events in his diary entries. His comments regarding the Civil War and the slavery issue during the 1860's are of interest, although Walker's location in northern New England precluded personal interaction with the events reported. During the 1890's Walker was particularly interested in national financial news regarding currency and taxes. Newspaper clippings pasted into the diaries deal primarily with unusual local weather conditions or national news events. Local details such as ice-skating conditions and the spring arrival of the 'Baltimore orioles" are also documented. Daily weather conditions are consistently reported in Walker's personal entries.
The diaries of George Leon Walker also provide biographical information about his son, Williston. Williston Walker wrote the entries in his father's diary from August to October, 1896, following his father's debilitating stroke.
The miscellaneous records of Series II primarily relate to George Leon Walker, supplementing the biographical overview provided by his diaries. They include:
A. Records of sermons preached: Two volumes record the sermons preached by Walker from 1857 to 1896, indicating the date, location and text preached on.
B. Pastoral records: One record book documents the marriages (1858-1882), funerals (1857-1884) and baptisms (1858-1879) performed by Walker. The date of the ceremony and names of individuals involved are provided, as well as the age of the deceased in the case of funerals and an indication of adult or infant baptism. Another small volume includes a marriage service written out by Walker followed by a record of marriages performed from 1858 to 1896 (which in part duplicates the records noted above).
In May of 1886 Walker entered into a notebook a list of all books and pictures which he owned.
Another small notebook contains "a record of the account of the N. B. Williston and Co. Carriage Shop with the First National Bank", (1870-1878). This copy of the original was made by young Williston Walker and its "accuracy attested to"by his father.
A day book for a store in Amherst, Massachusetts records business transacted in January of 1883.
A collection of early accounts of benefactions, sermons, and other material relating to or by Rev. Joseph Fish, Pastor of the Second Congregational Church of Stonington completes the Series.
Prominent correspondents of the Walkers in Series III include Lyman Abbott, Leonard Bacon, Henry Ward Beecher, Samuel Langhorne Clemens, Timothy Dwight, George Park Fisher, Washington Gladden, Mark Hopkins, Dwight L. Moody, Theodore Thornton Munger, Noah Porter, Julius Seelye, and Newman Smyth. A number of letters in the Series relate to the controversy surrounding the applications for missionary service under the A.B.C.F.M. of A. J. Covell and Charles Harbutt in 1887. These letters are an excellent source of documentation regarding the questions of doctrinal orthodoxy that concerned the Board during this era.
The writings, addresses and sermons of Series IV are primarily those of Williston Walker and their contents reflect his interests. Also included in the Series are 53 manuscript sermons of Payson Williston, Pastor of the church in Easthampton, Massachusetts from 1789 to 1833, and a 1722 manuscript sermon of Rev. Elisha Williams who was Rector of Yale College from 1726 to 1739.
The notes of Series V are primarily those of Williston Walker. They include narrative notes for lectures Walker delivered as Titus Street Professor of Ecclesiastical History at Yale.
The final Series represents a collection of manuscript and printed documents collected by George Leon and Williston Walker on subjects of interest to them.
Arrangement
I. Diaries of George Leon Walker
II. Miscellaneous Records
III. Correspondence
IV. Writings, Addresses, Sermons
V. Notes
VI. Personal Items and Memorabilia
Church work -- Congregationalism; Congregationalists -- New England; Sermons, American; Slavery; Universities and colleges -- Religion; Weather; United States -- Religion; Diaries; Authors; Clergy; Deans; Educators; Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925; Dwight, Timothy, 1828-1916; Fisher, George Park, 1827-1909; Gladden, Washington, 1836-1918; Moody, Dwight Lyman, 1837-1899; Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1830-1910; Porter, Noah, 1811-1892; Seelye, Julius H. (Julius Hawley), 1824-1895; Smyth, Newman, 1843-1925; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Walker, George Leon, 1830-1900; Walker, Williston, 1860-1922; Williams, Elisha, 1694-1755; Wright, Henry B. (Henry Burt), 1877-1923; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions; Andover Theological Seminary; First Church of Christ (Hartford, Conn.); Yale University
- Diaries, 1861 Mar-1863 Nov; Series I
  - Vol. 1, 1861 Mar-1863 Nov (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 2, 1862 Nov- 1864 Jul (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 3, 1864 Jul-1865 Nov (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 4, 1865 Nov-1866 Dec (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 5, 1866 Dec-1867 Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 6, 1867 Nov-1868 Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 7, 1869 Jan-Dec (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 8, 1870 Jan-1872 Oct (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 9, 1872 Oct-1875 Apr (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 10, 1875 Apr-1878 Dec (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Vol. 11, 1879 Jan- 1882 Apr (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Vol. 12, 1882 Apr-1886 Apr (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Vol. 13, 1886 May-1888 Jul (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Vol. 14, 1890 Aug-1893 Sep (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Vol. 15, 1893 Sep-1895 May (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 16, 1895 May-1896 Oct (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Small notebook diary of "Atlantic trip", 1880 Aug-Sep (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Diary of Amelia Lamed Walker, 1898 Jan-Feb, Oct (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1857 Sep- 1878 Jun; Series II
  - Record book of sermons preached, 1857 Sep- 1878 Jun (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Record book of sermons preached, 1878 Jun-1896 May (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Record book of marriages, funerals and baptisms performed, 1857-1884 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Marriage service and records, 1858-1896 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Inventory of books and pictures owned by G.L.W., 1886 May (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Record of the account of the N.B. Williston and Co. Carriage Shop with the First National Bank, 1870-1878 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Day book of store in Amherst, Mass., 1883 Jan (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Accounts of benefactions, sermons, and other material relating to or by Rev. Joseph Fish, Pastor of 2nd Congregational Church of Stonington, 1732-1781 (Box 4, Folder 24A)
- Correspondence, Series III
  - George Leon Walker
    - Letters Received
      - Abbott, Lyman (3), 1882, 1888, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Bacon, Leonard (2), 1879 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Bancroft, Cecil F. P. (2), 1896, n. d. (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Barbour, William M., 1879 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - Bartlett, Samuel C., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Bassett, William G. (4), 1895, 1896, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Battell, Robbins, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Beecher, Henry Ward, 1883 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Bowles, Samuel, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - British Museum, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Bromley, Isaac H. (2), 1891,1892 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Budington, Wm. Ives, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Burton, Nathaniel, 1879 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Cable, George W., 1886 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Chamberlain, Mellen, 1884, 1887 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Chesebrough, Amos S., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Churchill (J. W.?), 1896 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Clark, N. G., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Coe, David B. (2), 1882 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Covell, A. J., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Day, George Edward (2), 1890, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Dexter, Franklin B., 1887 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Dwight, Timothy (15), 1888-1895 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Fisher, George Park (4), 1879-1893 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Fiske, D. T. (2), 1895, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Gladden, Washington (2), 1882, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Gould, G.H., 1879 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Gullivin, J. P. (2), 1893 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Harbutt, Charles, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Hartrault, C. D., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Hawes, J., 1979 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Hayden, Jabez Haskell, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Hopkins, Mark, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Karr, W. S. (3), 1887, 1888, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Magoun, George F., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Mead, C. M., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Mead, H., 1880 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Mitchell, Donald G., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Monroe, E. B., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Morrill, Justin S., 1878 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Palmer, Ray, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Park, Edwards A. (2), 1891, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Porter, Noah (2), 1883, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Quint, Alonzo Hall (3), 1890, 1895, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Richardson, E.H., 1879 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Robinson, Henry C., 1887 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Smith, George Williamson, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Smith, Judson, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Smyth, Egbert C., 1889 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Smyth, Newman, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Storrs, R. P. (7), 1878-1894 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Swing, David, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Taft, Royal C., 1890 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      - Taylor, John Phelps, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Taylor, William M. (2), 1882,1889 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Thompson, William, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Walker, Joseph B., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Ward, William Hayes, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Wolcott, Samuel, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Yale University Library, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Unidentified, fragment (3), 1889,1892,1893
    - Letters Sent
      - Judson Smith, 1890 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Letters Introducing GLW to John Jay Knox
      - Burnside, Ambrose E., 1878 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Evarts, William M., 1878 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Morgan, Edwin D., 1878 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      - Morrill, Justin S., 1878 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Williston Walker
    - Letters Received
      - Adams, Charles F. (3), 1894 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Adams, George B., 1888 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Adams, Oscar Fay, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Ballantine, William G., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Barbour, Lucius (2), 1913,1916 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      - Bassett, William G., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Beardsley, Morris B. (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Bradford, A. H., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Brewster, Chauncey G., 1908 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Briggs, A. C., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Brown, William Adams, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      - Burrage, Henry S., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Campbell, Douglas (4), 1891, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Chamberlain, Mellen (2), 1891, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1889 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Colt, Elizabeth H., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Comba, E., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Curtis, Lewis B., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 38)
      - Delisle, L., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Ely, Richard T., 1891 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Farnam, Henry W., 1917 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Fisher, George Park, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Fiske, Franklin W., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Foster, Frank H., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Gay, Frank B., 1916 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Gilman, Daniel C., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Gordon, George A. (2), 1909 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Hadley, Arthur T., 1905 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Hall, Arthur C. A., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Harris (?), George, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Hazleton, Sophie M., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      - Henson, Hensley (2), 1912 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Hill, Hamilton A. (2), 1892 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Hincks, Edward Y., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Hopkins, E. Washburn, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Hurst, John F., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Jacobs, Henry E., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 41)
      - Jamison, William R., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Joy, C. H., 1894 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Lamson, C. M., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Little, Arthur (3), 1896, 1897, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Lobstein (?), 1906 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Loofs, Friedrich, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Luchaire, Achille, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Macdonald, Hemean, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Mathews, Shailer, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Moody, Dwight L., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Moore, George J., 1919 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Morris, E. D., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Munger, Theodore Thornton, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Park, Edwards A., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Parsnis, J. C., 1894 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Peabody, Francis G., 1905 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Peel, Albert, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Penrose, Stephen B. L., 1902 (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Perry, John H., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 44)
      - Quint, Alonzo Hall, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Randolph, J. F., 1914 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Seelye, Julius H. (2), 1890, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Smyth, Eghert C. (2), 1889 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Steiner, Bernard C., 1894 (Box 5, Folder 45)
      - Storrs, Richard P., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Taft, Royal C., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Thacher, Peter, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Thomas, Allen C., 1889 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Thompson, James Westfall, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Tyler, W. S., 1892 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Van Dyke, Paul, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Walker, Francis A., 1893 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Wellman, Joshua W., 1898 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Wells, Charles T., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Wendell, Barrett (2), 1892, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Wernle, Paul, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Wolf, E. A., 1895 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Wright, Henry B., 1917 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Letters Sent
      - Adams, Charles Francis, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Campbell, Douglas, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Quint, Alonzo Hall (copy), 1896 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Secretary of the Board of Visitors of Andover Seminary (copy), 1896 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Warren, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous Letters
    - Edward S. Livermore to William Page (A.L.S.), 1797 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - E. TenEyck to William Gould and Co. (A.L.S.), 1813 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Charles B. Storrs to Charles Walker (A.L.S.), 1831 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Salmon Portland Chase to N. R. (B?) Williston (facsimile A.L.S.), 1861 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Mark Hopkins ret Dr. and Mrs. Lewellyn Pratt, 1881 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Letters to/from Charles Harbutt and members of Prudential Committee of ABCFM ret Harbutt's application for, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Mary Eleanor Wilkins to Amelia R. (Larned) Walker (A.L.S.), 1887 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - D. C. Greene to George Park Fisher (A.L.S.), 1889 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - N. G. Clark to F. N. White (T.L.S.), 1889 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - M. L. Gordon to J. H. DeForest (A.L.S.), 1889 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - E. B. Webb to A. J. Covell (A.L.S.), 1890 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - J. H. DeForest to George Park Fisher (A.L.S.), 1890 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - E. K. Alden to A. J. Covell (A.L.S.), 1890 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Otis Cary to J. H. DeForest (A.L.S.), 1890 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Mary B. S. Gillett to Alice (Masher) Walker (A.L.S.), 1900 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Heyward G. Leavitt to Henry F. Walker ret Tri State Land Co. (3 T.L.S., 1 A.L.S., 1 telegram, notes), 1904-1906 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - E. Elmer Faye, secretary of Old Colony 1904-1906 Trust Co., to Henry F. Walker (3 T.L.S.), 1922 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Wm. P. Downes to John C. Schwab, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Grace B. Lowe to Ralph W. Cutler, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Katie B. Jenkings to Ralph W. Cutler (A.L.S.), 1917 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - William Jennings Bryan to Livingstone W. Cleveland (A.L.S.), 1921,1922 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Livingstone W. Cleveland to William Jennings Bryan (T.L.), 1921 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Goodall to Alice (Masher) Walker (A.L.S.), 1922 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Excerpts from letters of Lieut. C of the French Cavalry, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Writings, Addresses, Sermons, Series IV
  - George Leon Walker
    - Printed Sermons and Essays
      - History of the First Church in Hartford, 1633-1883 (annotated copy with mss. inserted and laid in), 1884 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - Thirteen printed sermons, preached in Portland, ME; Manshester, VT; Rutland, VT; Hartford, CT (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Williston Walker
    - Autograph and Typewritten Manuscripts
      - Address to Connecticut Society of Colonial Wars Address commemorating 200th anniversary of 1909 Connecticut General Association (fragment), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 56)
      - "Are We Expecting Too Much of a College President?", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - "Changes in Congregationalism", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - "Infant Salvation", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - "The Integration of the University", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 57)
      - "James Madison", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - "Jonathan Edwards", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - re: Philip, Landgrave of Hesse (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - "The Pilgrims", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - "The Saybrook Platform", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Sermon from Matthew VI:12, 1896 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - "The War and Church Unity" (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Untitled, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - Fragment, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Printed Essays and Addresses
      - "Are Our Seminaries Maintaining the Quality of our Ministry?" (Hartford Seminary Record), 1897 (Box 7, Folder 60)
      - "Changes in Theology Among American Congregationalists" (American Journal of Theology), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 60)